elektrobit.com 2019-06-05

# Data privacy notice - Elektrobit

We appreciate your visit on our website elektrobit.com and your interest in our company. The protection of your personal data is very important to us.

In the following, we describe which information we collect when you visit our website and how this information is used.  
**For further information how personal data is processed at Elektrobit click** [here](https://www.elektrobit.com/dataprotection-information/).

Since personal data are under special legal protection, they are only collected by us insofar as this is necessary for the provision of our website and our services.

Our data protection practice complies with the statutory regulations, in particular those of the Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG-neu), the Telemedia Act (TMG) and the EU Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We will only collect, process and store your personal data, as long as this is necessary for provision of this website, our content and services, as well as for processing inquiries and, if necessary, processing orders / contracts, but only to the extent permitted by legitimate interest, Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. f GDPR, or another permit. Only if you have given your consent separately, you data may be used for the purposes stated in that consent declaration, e.g. for sending advertisement via newsletter.

## **Controller in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 GDPR**

Person responsible within the meaning of the GDPR, other national data protection laws of the member states or any other data protection regulations is:

Elektrobit Automotive GmbH  
Am Wolfsmantel 46  
91058 Erlangen  
E-Mail: [inquiries@elektrobit.com](mailto:inquiries@elektrobit.com)  
Tel.: +49 9131 7701-0  
Executives / authorized representatives: Alexander Kocher, Gregor Zink

## **Data Protection Officer**

To contact our Data Protection Officer please turn to:

MKM Datenschutz GmbH  
Äußere Sulzbacher Str. 124a  
90491 Nürnberg  
+49 911 669577 55  

Your contact person is Sven Sperling.

## **Provision of the website and creation of log files**

Every time our website is accessed, our system automatically collects data and information from your computer. The following data is collected:

(1) Information about the browser type and version used  
(2) The operating system of your computer  
(3) Your IP address  
(4) Date and time of access  
(5) Websites and resources (images, files, other page content) that were accessed on our website.  
(6) Websites via which the user has accessed our Website (Referrer tracking)

This data is saved as a Log File in our System. It will not be matched with any personal information so that linking it to an individual is not possible.

  * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data**  
6 para. 1 para. f GDPR (legitimate interest). Our legitimate Interest is to achieve the subsequent purpose.
  * **Purpose of data processing**  
We create Log Files to maintain the compatibility of our website for all visitors, to prevent abuse and errors. For this purpose, it is necessary to log the technical data, in order to be able to react as quickly as possible to prevent errors, attacks on our IT systems and/ or errors in the functionality of our website. In addition, the data is used to optimize the website and generally ensure the security of our information technology systems.
  * **Duration of storage**  
We delete this technical data as soon as it is no longer needed, but never later the 3 months after your visit.
  * **Option to object and erase your data**  
Your rights to objection and erasure to this processing are described further down in this privacy notice.
  * **Special features of the website**  
Our Website contains various functionalities which will collect, process and store your personal data.

## **Contact forms**

  * **Extent of processing of personal data**  
The data entered by you into our contact forms.
  * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data**  
6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR (the data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her personal data)
  * **Purpose of data processing**  
The data recorded through our contact form will only be used to process that specific contact request.
  * **Duration of storage**  
After processing your request, the collected data will be deleted immediately, as long as there are no legal storage periods.
  * **Option to object and erase your data**  
Your rights to objection and erasure to this processing are described further down in this privacy notice.

## **Login area**

  * **Extent of processing of personal data**  
The registration and login details you have entered.
  * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data**  
6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR (the data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her personal data)
  * **Purpose of data processing**  
You have the option to use a separate login area on our website. If you forgot your password or username, you have the possibility to have them re-sent after entering your email address. The resulting usage data will only be collected, stored and processed by us for the purpose of preventing and correcting malfunctions or maintaining the functionality. Any usage for other purposes or a data transfer to third parties will not take place.
  * **Duration of storage**  
The collected data will be stored as long as you maintain a user account with us. The data, which is collected within the function ‘Forgotten user name or password’, will only be used to re-send said data.
  * **Option to object and erase your data**  
Your rights to objection and erasure to this processing are described further down in this privacy notice.

## **Newsletter registration Form**

  * **Extent of processing of personal data**  
The data entered by you when signing up for the newsletter. You can subscribe to our newsletter on our website in order to receive information on our products, services and events. We use the data you provide us with within the scope of the approval given by you to send you our newsletter.  
In order to verify your identity, the subscription is processed by use of a double opt-in procedure.  After entering your data on our website, you will first receive a confirmation by e-mail. Only by clicking a button in our confirmation e-mail, the application process will be completed.  
You may at any time unsubscribe from our newsletter by the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our newsletter.  
To optimize our newsletter process we are using the tool ExactTarget. ExactTarget uses so called Web Beacons to document if our email are read and if servers are capable to receive HTML emails. Web Beacons are small files, which are activated, when an email is opened. This allows us to to see which emails are opened and also which links in our emails are clicked.
  * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data**  
6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR (the data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her personal data)
  * **Purpose of data processing**  
The data recorded in the newsletter registration form will exclusively be used by us to distribute our newsletter. After signing up, we will send you a confirmation e-mail containing a link that you must click to complete the registration (Double-Opt-In).
  * **Duration of storage**  
Our newsletter can be unsubscribed at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link, included in every newsletter. After unsubscribing your data will be deleted immediately. In case of an incomplete registration your data will also be deleted immediately.
  * **Option to object and erase your data**  
Your rights to objection and erasure to this processing are described further down in this privacy notice.

## **Statistical analysis and evaluation of visits to this website – web tracker**

We collect, process and store the following data when visiting this website or accessing individual files on this website: IP address, website from which the file was accessed from, file name, date and time of access, amount of data downloaded/ accessed and message of successful download/ access (so-called web log). We use this access data exclusively in a non-personalized form for the continuous improvement of our website and for statistical purposes. We also use the following web trackers to evaluate the visits to this website:

  * **Adobe Typekit**  
On our website, we use a web tracking service provided by Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited, 4-6 Riverwalk Citywest Business Campus, 24 Dublin, Ireland (hereafter: Adobe Typekit). As part of the web tracking, Adobe Typekit uses cookies that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of our website and your surfing behavior (so-called “tracking”). We use Adobe Typekit tracking service in order to constantly optimize our internet presence. By accessing our website, data, including your IP address and website usage, is transferred to Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited and also stored outside the European Union, e.g. processed and stored in the US. The EU Commission has determined that an adequate level of data protection is possible in the US if the data processing company has submitted to the US-EU Privacy Shield Agreement which is the case with Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <http://www.adobe.com/privacy.html>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) or disabling the “Do Not Track” option in your browser you can prevent Facebook from collecting (including the IP address), transferring and processing personal data. An opt-out option is available for download at the following link: <https://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/opt-out.html>
  * **Google Tag Manager**
    *     * **Extent of processing of personal data**  
On our site we use the services of Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (hereafter: Google Tag Manager). Google Tag Manager provides a technical platform to run and bundle other web services and web tracking programs using so-called tags. In this context, Google Tag Manager saves cookies on your computer and, as far as web tracking tools are run using Google Tag Manager, analyzes your surfing behavior (so-called “tracking”). The data sent by individual tags embedded in Google Tag Manager is collected, stored, and processed by Google Tag Manager under a user interface. All incorporated “tags” will be listed separately in this privacy policy. For more information on the privacy of the tools incorporated into Google Tag Manager, please go to the corresponding section of this privacy policy. When you use our website with Google Tag Manager tags enabled, data such as your IP address and user activity will be transmitted to servers of Google Ireland Limited and used outside the European Union, e.g. processed and stored in the US. The EU Commission has determined that an adequate level of data protection is possible in the US if the data processing company has submitted to the US-EU Privacy Shield Agreement which is the case with Google Ireland Limited. The web services included with Google Tag Manager are subjected to the terms in the corresponding section of this Privacy Policy. The tracking tools used in Google Tag Manager ensure that the IP address of Google Tag Manager is anonymized before transmission, by anonymizing the source code IP. Therefore Google Tag Manager can only collect anonymous IP-addresses (IP masking).
    * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data**  
6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR (Consent), either when registering with Google (by opening a Google Account and accepting the privacy notices) or, if you have not registered with Google, by explicitly agreeing to open our page.
    * **Purpose of data processing**  
Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate your visit to this website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide us with other services related to website activity and internet usage. The IP address provided by Google Tag Manager from your browser will not be merged with other data from Google Ireland Limited.
    * **Duration of storage**  
Google will store the data as long as necessary to fulfill this web service. The data collection and storage is done anonymously. If any non-anonymized personal data is collected, it will be deleted immediately, as far as they are not subject to legal storage obligations. In any case, the deletion takes place after expiry of the storage obligation.
    * **Option to object and erase your data**  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) or disabling the “Do Not Track” option in your browser you can prevent Google from collecting (including the IP address), transferring and processing of personal data. In addition, you may prevent the collection of data generated by Google’s Cookie, related to your website usage history (including your IP address) as well its processing by installing the plugin found at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. Google’s security and privacy policies can be found at <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

  * **Twitter Advertising**  
We use a web tracker by Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street, D02 AX07 Dublin 2, Ireland (hereafter: Twitter Advertising). As part of this web tracking service, Twitter Advertising uses the web tracking cookies stored on your computer to analyze the website and your surfing behavior. We use Twitter Advertising tracking service in order to constantly optimize our internet presence. By accessing our website, data, including your IP address and website usage, is transferred to Twitter International Company and also stored outside the European Union, e.g. processed and stored in the US. The EU Commission has determined that an adequate level of data protection is possible in the US if the data processing company has submitted to the US-EU Privacy Shield Agreement. Twitter International Company is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (see https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://twitter.com/de/privacy>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) or disabling the “Do Not Track” option in your browser you can prevent Facebook from collecting (including the IP address), transferring and processing personal data. An opt-out option is available for download at the following link: <https://twitter.com/de/privacy>
  * **Google Analytics**
    *     * **Extent of processing of personal data**  
On our site we use the web tracking service of Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (hereafter: Google Analytics). Google Analytics uses the web tracking cookies stored on your computer to analyze the website and your surfing behavior. We use Google Analytics tracking service in order to constantly optimize our internet presence. By accessing our website, data, including your IP address and website usage, is transferred to Google Ireland Limited and also stored outside the European Union, e.g. processed and stored in the US. The EU Commission has determined that an adequate level of data protection is possible in the US if the data processing company has submitted to the US-EU Privacy Shield Agreement which is the case with Google Ireland Limited. By activating IP anonymization in the Google Analytics tracking code of this website, your IP address will be anonymized by Google Analytics before transmission. This website uses a Google Analytics tracking code that includes gat._anonymizeIp (). This allows for a solely anonymized IP-address collection.
    * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data** 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR (Consent), either when registering with Google (by opening a Google Account and accepting the privacy notices) or, if you have not registered with Google, by explicitly agreeing to open our page.
    * ****Purpose of data processing**** Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate your visit to this website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide us with other services related to website activity and internet usage. The IP address provided by Google Tag Manager from your browser will not be merged with other data from Google Ireland Limited.
    * **Duration of storage** Google will store the data relevant to the provision of the web tracking as long as necessary to fulfill the posted web service. The data collection and storage is done anonymously. As far as personal reference should exist, the data will be deleted immediately, as far as they are not subject to legal storage obligations. In any case, the deletion takes place after expiry of the storage obligation.
    * **Option to object and erase your data** By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) or disabling the “Do Not Track” option in your browser you can prevent Google from collecting (including the IP address), transferring and processing personal data. In addition, you may prevent the collection of data generated by Google’s Cookie, related to your website usage history (including your IP address) as well its processing by installing the plugin found at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. Google’s security and privacy policies can be found at <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

  * **Facebook Connect**  
We use a web tracker by Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, 2 Dublin, Ireland (hereafter: Facebook Connect). As part of this web tracking service, Facebook Connect uses the web tracking cookies stored on your computer to analyze the website and your surfing behavior. We use Facebook Connect tracking service in order to constantly optimize our internet presence. By accessing our website, data, including your IP address and website usage, is transferred to Facebook Ireland Limited and also stored outside the European Union, e.g. processed and stored in the US. The EU Commission has determined that an adequate level of data protection is possible in the US if the data processing company has submitted to the US-EU Privacy Shield Agreement. Facebook Ireland Limited is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (see https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>. By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) or disabling the “Do Not Track” option in your browser you can prevent Facebook from collecting (including the IP address), transferring and processing personal data. An opt-out option is available for download at the following link: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>

## **Integration of external web services and processing of data outside the EU**

We use active Java Script content from external providers, so-called web services. By accessing our website these external providers may receive personal information about your visit to our website. A data transfer outside the EU is possible. You can prevent this by using a java script blocker such as ‘NoScript’ (found at [www.noscript.net](http://www.noscript.net/)) or disabling JavaScript in your browser. This may result in functional restrictions on websites you visit. We use the following external web services:

  * **AddThis**  
We use a web service from Oracle America, Inc., 500 Oracle Parkway, 94065 Redwood Shores, California , USA (hereinafter: AddThis) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to AddThis. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. Oracle America, Inc. is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Doubleclick from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **Amazon CloudFront (CDN)**  
The web service Amazon CloudFront by Amazon Europe Core S.à.r.l., 5 Rue Plaetis, 2338 Luxembourg, Luxembourg (hereafter: Amazon CloudFront (CDN)) is used on our website. We use its data to ensure the full functionality of our website. Thus your browser may transfer personal information to Amazon CloudFront (CDN). The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=201909010.  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Amazon CloudFront (CDN) from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **Bootstrapcdn.com**  
We use a web service from NetDNA LLC, Cahuenga Blvd Suite 630, 90068 Los Angeles, USA (hereinafter: Bootstrapcdn.com) on our website. If you have enabled Java Script in your browser and have not installed a Java Script Blocker, your browser may transmit personal information to Bootstrapcdn.com. For more information please visit <https://www.bootstrapcdn.com/privacy-policy/>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Bootstrapcdn.com from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **CloudFlare**  
We use a web service from CloudFlare Inc., 101 Townsend St, 94107 San Francisco, USA (hereinafter: CloudFlare) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to CloudFlare. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. CloudFlare Inc. is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy/?utm_referrer=https://www.google.de/>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent CloudFlare from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **DoubleClick**  
We use a web service from Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, 4 Dublin, Ireland (hereinafter: Doubleclick) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to DoubleClick. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. Google Ireland Limited is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Doubleclick from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **Google**  
We use a web service from Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, 4 Dublin, Ireland (hereinafter: Google) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to Google. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. Google Ireland Limited is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Google from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **Google APIS**  
We use a web service from Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, 4 Dublin, Ireland (hereinafter: Google APIS) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to Google APIS. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. Google Ireland Limited is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Google APIS from collecting, transferring and processing personal data..
  * **Gstatic**  
We use a web service from Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, 4 Dublin, Ireland (hereinafter: Gstatic) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to Gstatic. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. Google Ireland Limited is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Gstatic from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **ShareThis**  
We use a web service from ShareThis, Inc., 4005 Miranda Avenue, 94304 Palo Alto, USA (hereinafter: ShareThis) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to ShareThis. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. ShareThis Inc. is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://www.sharethis.com/privacy/>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent ShareThis from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **Youtube**  
We use a web service from Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, 4 Dublin, Ireland (hereinafter: Youtube) on our Website. We use this data to ensure the full functionality of our website. In this context, your browser may submit personal information to Youtube. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The legitimate interest consists in a faultless function of the website. Google Ireland Limited is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement (https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). The data will be deleted as soon as it has fulfilled its purpose. For more information please visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
By installing a script code blocker (e.g. www.noscript.net or www.ghostery.com) you can prevent Youtube from collecting, transferring and processing personal data.
  * **Social Plug-In – “Twitter”**  
On our Website we have embedded a social plug-in from the social Network “Twitter” by Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place Fenian Street, 2 Dublin, Ireland (hereinafter: “Twitter”). By accessing a Webpage with a Twitter plug-in, your browser will establish a connection Twitter’s servers. The content of the plug-in is transmitted directly from Twitter to your browser and only integrated into our website. By that Twitter is notified whether you accessed a specific page on our website and will collect data like you IP adress. This information will be collected and sent to servers in Ireland regardless if you have an account on Twitter or not. If you have a Twitter profile, the collected information can be directly associated with it. Twitter will also collect information if you interact with the social Plug-In (e.g. by clicking the “Like” button or commenting). Depending on your account settings that information may be published on you Twitter profile and shown to your contacts. 
    * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data**  
Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR (if you are registered on “Twitter”) and Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR (if you are not registered on Twitter). If processing is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR, the legitimate interest is to enable users to interact with our content on Twitter.
    * **Purpose of data processing**  
The primary purpose of this data collection is to provide you with an opportunity for social interaction with Twitter and to make our website interactive. The extent of the data collection and the further processing and use of the collected data by Twitter as well as your rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy can be found at: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>
    * ****Duration of storage****  
Twitter will store the data as long as it is necessary to fulfil its web service. If the data is subject to legal storage obligations, they will be deleted after the expiry of the storage obligation period.
    * **Option to object and erase your data**  
If you do not want the social plug-in to be executed by Twitter, you can block its execution by installing a script blocker such as “NoScript”. If you do not want Twitter to associate the data collected via our website with your Twitter profile, you must log out of Twitter before visiting our website. You can also prevent Twitter plug-ins from loading by using add-ons for your browser.  
For Mozilla Firefox you will find the appropriate plug-ins under the following search: <https://addons.mozilla.org/en/firefox/>  
For Opera you will find the appropriate plugins under the following search: <https://addons.opera.com/en/>  
For Chrome you will find the appropriate plugins under the following search: <https://chrome.google.com/webstore/category/extensions?hl=en>  
Your rights to objection and erasure to this processing are described further down in this privacy notice.

## **Information about the use of cookies**

  * **Extent of processing of personal data**  
On various pages we use cookies to enable certain features on our website. Those ‘cookies’ are small text files that your browser stores on the computer. These text files contain an individual string that allows us to identify your browser when you visit our website again. The process of storing cookie files is also called ‘setting a cookie’.
  * **Legal basis for the processing of personal data**  
6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR (legitimate interest). Our legitimate interest is the preservation of the full functionality of our website, the increase in usability and the ability to provide a more personalized experience to the customer. The identification of individual site visitors is only possible, if by giving consent to the use of cookies, personal data is gathered.
  * **Purpose of data processing**  
Cookies are set in order to maintain the full functionality of our website and to improve its usability. In addition, cookie technology allows us to set individual aliases (an unique ID) to visitors so that we can offer more personalized services.
  * **Duration of storage**  
Our cookies will be stored until deletion in your browser or, in the case of a session cookie, until the session has expired.
  * **Option to object and erase your data**  
You can set your browser according to your wishes in such a way that the setting of cookies is generally prevented. You can either decide on a case-by-case basis which cookies are allowed or allow them entirely. Cookies can be used for different purposes, e.g. to analyze if your PC ever had a connection to our website (permanent cookies) or to save recently viewed offers (session cookies). We use cookies to provide you with an better user experience. Your rights to objection and erasure to this processing are described further down in this privacy notice.

## **Data security and data protection, communication by e-mail**

Your personal data will be protected by technical and organizational measures so that their collection, storage and processing are is accessible to third parties. In the case of unencrypted email communication, we cannot guarantee complete data security on the way to our IT systems. We recommend encrypted communication or postal mail for information requiring a high degree of secrecy.

## **Revocation of consent – Right to rectification and to data access– Right to erasure and to restriction of processing**

In appropriate intervals you have the right to obtain information about your stored data as well as the right to rectification, restriction of processing or deletion of your data at any time. Your data will be deleted by without undue delay, if this is not opposed by legal regulations. You can revoke a consent given to us to use your personal data at any time. Information, erasure and rectification requests for your data and any suggestions, you may send at any time to the following address of the data protection officer (see above)

## **Right to data portability  
**

You have the right to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You may also request that we transfer this data to a third party immediately upon your first instruction, provided that the processing is carried out through consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a) GDPR) or a contract (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR) and is processed by us as part of an automated data processing. Freedoms and rights of other persons may not be affected.  
The right to data portability does not apply to the processing of personal data necessary for the execution of a task in public interest or in exercise of official authority delegated to the controller.

## **Complaint right with the supervisory authority acc. Art. 77 para. 1 GDPR  
**

If you have the suspicion that your data is processed unlawfully on our site, you can of course always bring about a judicial clarification of the problem. Irrespective of this, you have the option of contacting a supervisory authority. You have the right to appeal in the EU Member State of residence, place of work and/or place of alleged infringement. The supervisory authority to which the complaint was submitted will then inform you of the status and results of your complaint, including the possibility of a judicial remedy under Art. 78 GDPR.
